# **Tom L Jenkins**

**PhD** 

**Curriculum Vitae** 



tomjenkins.netlify.app

Tom-Jenkins

#### **Profile**

Scientist specialising in bioinformatics, data analysis and R programming. I have a broad range of interests and knowledge in evolutionary biology, geospatial analysis and data science. Previous projects include population genomics and whole genome sequencing of marine species, genome assembly and trait-association modelling, and predicting habitat suitability using machine learning.

# **Employment**

Apr 2022-Present	Bioinformatician & Software Developer	Animal and Plant Health Agency
------------------	---------------------------------------	--------------------------------

Feb 2021–Mar 2022 Senior Data Analyst / Advisor Natural England
Dec 2018–Jan 2021 Postdoctoral Research Associate University of Exeter

### Qualifications

2018 F	PhD	Biological Sciences	University of Exeter
2014	MRes	Biodiversity, Informatics and Genomics	Imperial Colleage London
2010 E	BSc	Marine Biology	Swansea University

## **Computer Skills**

Proficient R Programming, Linux, Geocomputation, MS Office
Competent GitHub, AWS, R Markdown, R Shiny, Leaflet.js, ECharts.js

#### **Selected Awards and Talks**

2022	Talk	Live interview on BBC Radio Wales Drive to discuss published research on coral
		habitat suitability modelling
2021	Talk	Pre-recorded interview on BBC Radio Cornwall to discuss published research on
		red algae genomics
2019	Award	British Ecological Society Research Grant (£5,000)
2018	Talk	Invited talk at ARCH-UK Annual Science Event
2018	Award	Heredity Fieldwork Grant (£1,284)

#### **Selected Publications**

- ➤ Jenkins TL, Stevens JR (2022). Predicting habitat suitability and range shifts under projected climate change for two octocorals in the north-east Atlantic. PeerJ 10, e13509.
- ➤ Jenkins TL, Guillemin M-L, Simon-Nutbrown C, Burdett HL, Stevens JR, Peña V (2021). Whole genome genotyping reveals discrete genetic diversity in north-east Atlantic maerl beds. Evolutionary Applications 14, 1558–1571.
- ➤ Houston RD, Bean TP, Macqueen DJ, Gundappa MK, Jin YH, **Jenkins TL**, *et al*. (2020). Harnessing genomics to fast-track genetic improvement in aquaculture. Nature Reviews Genetics 21, 389–409.